Guide to the Blair Dean Utah natural bodybuilding video collection 1983-2001
Multimedia Archives, J. Willard Marriott Library, University of Utah
Blair Dean Utah natural bodybuilding video collection
1983-2001
University of Utah Libraries, Special Collections Audio Visual Archives Special Collections 295 South 1500 East Salt Lake City, Utah 84112-0860 801-581-8864 http://www.lib.utah.edu/collections/multimedia-archives/
A0077
Dean, Blair
17 VHS videocassettes
The Blair Dean Utah natural bodybuilding video collection (1983-2001) consists of video recordings of National Gym Association (NGA) natural bodybuilding competitions in Utah and other states. Blair Dean promoted these competitions for over thirty-five years.
Historical Note
Founded in 1979 by Andy Bostinto, the National Gym Association (NGA) is a non-profit organization whose mission is "to inform and support athletes through education, personal fitness training and certification programs" and to encourage "the art and science of natural strength training and bodybuilding." The NGA has supported "all natural" (drug free) professional and amateur bodybuilding competitions across the United States of America since the 1980s. Blair Dean has been a promoter of these competitions in Utah for over thirty-five years.
The Blair Dean Utah natural bodybuilding video collection (1983-2001) consists of video recordings of National Gym Association (NGA) natural bodybuilding competitions in Utah and other states. All videocassettes have been digitized and are available to view on the twelve DVDs detailed in this finding aid.
Materials are arranged chronologically.
Materials must be used on-site; no use of original material, access copies will be made available for viewing. Five business days advanced notice required. Access to parts of this collection may be restricted under provisions of state or federal law, condition of the material, or by donor.
Donated by Blair Dean in 2011.
National Gym Association; Utah; Bodybuilding.; Sports and Recreation; Moving Images; Moving images
- Utah Bodybuilding Championships, 1983; DVD (Disc 1)
  Announcer: Mike Runge
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 1990 May; DVD (Disc 2)
  Women's Masters winner: Sue Parsons (age 39). Men's Masters winner: Scott Tavish. Runner-up: Philip Walters.
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 1991 May 18; DVD (Disc 3)
  Teen winner: Jeff Boost. Men's Masters winner: Jaime Mariquez. Men's Medium Division winner: Steve Cook. Men's Small Division winner: Troy Wilkinson. Women's Medium Division winner: Sue Parsons. Women's Small Division winner: Donnal Wallace
- Utah Natural Novice Bodybuilding Championships, 1991 February 23; DVD (Disc 4)
  Teen winner: Jeff Boost
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 1992; DVD (Disc 5)
  Location: Salt Lake Community College.
- National Gym Association (NGA) Bodybuilding Championships, 1994; DVD (Disc 6)
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 1995 April 15; DVD (Disc 7)
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 1997 April 04; DVD (Disc 8)
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 1999; DVD (Disc 9)
- Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 2000; DVD (Disc 10)
- Bodybuilders and Hawaii, 2000; DVD (Disc 11)
  Bodybuilders pose on a beach in Hawaii. Some poses are upside down.
- Mountain States Open Bodybuilding Championships, 2000; DVD (Disc 12)
- NGA Mr. and Ms. Utah Natural Bodybuilding Championships, 2001; DVD (Disc 13)
  Location: Woods Cross High School in Bountiful, Utah. Hosted by a former Mr. Utah.